# Kartavya Saini

LinkedIn: <a href="https://rb.gy/jso39g">https://rb.gy/jso39g</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://rb.gy/4qswd6">https://rb.gy/4qswd6</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://rb.gy/aeitfv">https://rb.gy/aeitfv</a>

Phone: +61 410 742 021 | Email: kartavyas@gmail.com | Melbourne, AU

#### **SUMMARY:**

Full stack web developer leveraging a background in sales and marketing to provide the best user experience for web application development. Obtained a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Monash University's intensive 24-week coding boot camp. Adaptive problem-solver who loves to develop apps with focus on mobile-first design and development. Strengths in adaptability, detail-orientation, creativity, communication, problem-solving, teamwork, time-management, leadership, perseverance, and building projects from concept to completion.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

#### Languages:

JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

#### **Application:**

React, TDD, MongoDB, MySQL, ,MVC, Third Party APIs, Object Oriented Programing/Design(OOP), Object Relational Programming (ORM), Progressive Web Applications (PWA), Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, JSON, BootStrap

#### Tools:

Git. Heroku. MS Office.

#### **Productivity**:

Slack, Microsoft Office Suits, Zoom

#### **PROJECTS:**

Together Fitness | GITHUB: https://rb.gy/iwtxtq | DEPLOYED : https://rb.gy/dxz7fq

- **Summary:** Using Together Fitness users can search through the list of workouts and can choose the workout with its location plus users can create workout.
- **Tools:** Node.js, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, JAWSDB, Heroku, JQuery, Bootstrap, Dotenv, BCrypt Hash Password, Geolocation API, Google Place API

## Search it | GITHUB : <a href="https://rb.gy/fjzj2a">https://rb.gy/pcfsxc</a> | DEPLOYED : <a href="https://rb.gy/pcfsxc">https://rb.gy/pcfsxc</a>

- **Summary:** A search based web application which will allow the user to gain information in the form of videos and data.
- Tools: YouTube API, Wikipedia API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

# **Team Profile Generator** | GITHUB : <a href="https://rb.gy/nwvile">https://rb.gy/fo5i3m</a>

- **Summary:** A command-line application takes in information about employees and generates an HTML web page that renders summaries for each person.
- **Tools:** JavaScript, NodeJS, Jest package, Inquire package, Bootstrap.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

**Dnata Catering,** Melbourne, AU — Domestic Consolidator **January 2022 - PRESENT** 

- Responsible for ensuring in-flight meals for Qantas domestic flights
- Achieved Quality and Quantity standards as per flight requirements.

**Ultra Scrap Metal,** Melbourne, AU — Director

June 2017 - August 2020

- Built a scrap metal trading business specialized in different Stainless Steel grades.
- Succeeded in purchasing container loads from different scrap yards and supplying to foundries and mills in India.

TNT Express NZ ltd, Auckland, AU — Account Manager July 2015 - Jan 2017

- Managed geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum.
- Enhanced customer base of geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum by upselling, cross selling or acquiring new business.

#### **EDUCATION:**

**Monash University,** Melbourne — Full-Stack Web Development Certificate February 2022 - August 2022

24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills

**Alliance Française**, India — Diploma in French language

March 2004 - June 2006

French language

**Gujarat University**, India — Bachelor of Commerce

June 2000 - April 2003

Advance Accounting and Auditing